Chante Douglas

71 Glenstroke Drive Scarborough, ON M1S 3A1 (647) 466-6225 chanted0731@gmail.com

Profile

Honours Professional Writing student at York University. Proficient in writing, editing, and research. Advanced skills in organization, planning, verbal and written communication, and data recording. Experience in assisting with project and program planning, with skills in creating and editing a variety of documents, proposals, presentations, and reports while working both independently and with a team.

Education

Honours Bachelor of Professional Writing

Expected 2023

York University, Toronto, Ontario

Experience

York University SSRP Special Projects Assistant

05/2021 - Present

- Creates PowerPoint presentations that are used to distribute information to both partner groups and colleagues
- Supports the planning and organization of special projects and activities
- Formats and edits a variety of documents and materials
- Documents and attends team meetings to discuss project plans
- Takes meeting minutes, records actionable items, and ensures appropriate follow-up
- Prepares and disseminates meeting agendas and supporting information
- Assists with the distribution of project plans and progress tracking
- Assists with research, recommendations, and the presenting of ideas for special projects
- Visualizes data reports for tracking using PowerBI

York University WUSC Committee Executive Member

05/2021 - Present

- Responsible for management in the communications, events, advocacy, outreach, and logistics areas
- Attends meetings with other executive members to discuss current and future plans for the committee
- Coordinates with the Chair and/or Vice Chair to oversee all events and initiatives within the committee
- Creates posters using Canva and uploads them to the committee's social media pages to advertise fundraising, social, and recruitment events
- Assists in managing the monthly projected schedule for the committee's social media

- Collaborates with members of each department team to assist in the planning of events and the delegation and distribution of tasks to streamline task completion
- Creates new event ideas and coordinates and manages events to ensure events are run and completed efficiently
- Ensures that timelines are adhered to, and establishes deadlines where necessary

York University Existere Journal Junior Editor

10/2020 - 09/2022

- Reviews and edits up to 10 submissions per week
- Works in a collaborative setting with other editors to read, critically assess, discuss, and select works of fiction submitted by national and international artists

Bleecker Wellesley Activity Network Office Assistant

09/2019 - 07/2020

- Upheld schedule to ensure daily business needs were met
- Provided exceptional customer service by tending to client concerns and confirming appointments
- Used advanced verbal communication skills to plan and manage office responsibilities
- Performed data entry concerning private client information
- Tended to office inquiries over phone, email, and in-person
- Used verbal and active listening communication skills to help clients
- Made calls to over 40 clients to collect, review, update, and verify information
- Used the internet to gather data and provide recommendations for clients
- Performed data entry concerning client information
- Advanced communication skills from working with other volunteers and helping visitors
- Recorded information while reporting to supervisor through both verbal and written communication

Technical Skills

- Experienced in working with Jira, PowerBI, Microsoft Office, Excel (Spreadsheets), GitHub, Word, email, and the internet
- Ability to summarize, analyze, and input data according to the internet and other sources
- Ability to input data online while paying attention to detail
- Proficient in online research